<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-03-14T11:59:57+00:00</updated><id>https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tech Bootcamp 2: Makers Academy (Software Engineering)</title><link href="https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/blog/2024/makers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Bootcamp 2: Makers Academy (Software Engineering)"/><published>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/blog/2024/makers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/blog/2024/makers/"><![CDATA[<p>As I reflect on my journey through Makers Academy, I’m filled with a sense of accomplishment and growth. Each module of the course has been a stepping stone towards becoming a proficient software engineer, equipped with essential skills and experiences that prepare me for the challenges of the industry. Let’s delve into my experiences in each module:</p> <h2 id="module-1-python-foundations">Module 1: Python Foundations</h2> <p>In Module 1, I laid the groundwork for my programming journey. From mastering command line navigation to delving into the intricacies of Git version control, every skill acquired paved the way for efficient project development and organization. The practical application of Python programming further diversified my portfolio, while embracing challenges honed my problem-solving abilities.</p> <h2 id="module-2-the-golden-square-challenges">Module 2: The Golden Square Challenges</h2> <p>Module 2 was a testament to my growth as a software engineer. Through mastering Test-Driven Development (TDD) and delving into object-oriented design, I learned to create well-structured, reliable code. The experience of pair programming not only enhanced my technical skills but also fortified my communication and teamwork abilities.</p> <h2 id="module-3-databases">Module 3: Databases</h2> <p>In Module 3, I ventured into the realm of database management. From designing intricate database schemas to integrating them seamlessly with programs, I gained invaluable insights into data organization and retrieval. The ability to communicate effectively with databases further solidified my understanding of data flow within applications.</p> <h2 id="module-4-web-applications">Module 4: Web Applications</h2> <p>Module 4 marked my foray into web application development. Understanding the nuances of HTTP and mastering integration testing were crucial milestones. Implementing web routes and debugging applications sharpened my skills in creating dynamic, reliable web solutions.</p> <h2 id="module-5-cloud-deployment">Module 5: Cloud Deployment</h2> <p>Module 5 elevated my understanding of cloud deployment and continuous integration and deployment (CI-CD). From grasping the deployment process to deploying complex database-backed web applications, every achievement underscored my readiness to tackle real-world challenges in a cloud environment.</p> <h2 id="module-6-engineering-project-makersbnb">Module 6: Engineering Project (Makersbnb)</h2> <p>The culmination of my journey at Makers Academy was the Engineering Project - Makersbnb. This collaborative endeavor not only showcased my technical prowess but also highlighted my adeptness in teamwork and agile project management. From effective task breakdown to meticulous user story planning, every aspect of the project was a testament to our collective efforts and dedication.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>My experience at Makers Academy has been nothing short of transformative. From mastering programming fundamentals to navigating complex engineering projects, each module has been instrumental in shaping me into a well-rounded software engineer. As I embark on the next chapter of my journey, I carry with me not just the technical skills, but also the resilience, adaptability, and teamwork ethos instilled during my time at Makers Academy. I am excited to apply these learnings in the real world, confident in my ability to make meaningful contributions to the field of software development.</p> <h2 id="demo-day-project-presentation">Demo Day Project Presentation</h2> <p><img src="/assets/img/demoday_1.png" width="100%" height="100%"/></p> <p><img src="/assets/img/demoday_2.png" width="100%" height="100%"/></p> <p><img src="/assets/img/demoday_3.png" width="100%" height="100%"/></p> <p><img src="/assets/img/demoday_4.png" width="100%" height="100%"/></p> <div style="position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/luQzgdvhhMQ?start=1533" style="position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%; left: 0; top: 0;" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My experience at Makers Academy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech Bootcamp 1: Generation UK (IT &amp;amp; Cybersecurity)</title><link href="https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/blog/2024/generation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Bootcamp 1: Generation UK (IT &amp;amp; Cybersecurity)"/><published>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/blog/2024/generation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ahmedkordofani.github.io/blog/2024/generation/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="day-1-5">Day 1-5</h2> <p>Embarking on my IT journey with Generation UK was an exhilarating experience. From lively discussions to hands-on labs, each day brought new insights and challenges. We delved into technical aspects, honed our communication skills, and began roleplaying to prepare for real-world scenarios.</p> <h2 id="day-6-10">Day 6-10</h2> <p>As the days progressed, so did our learning. From perfecting our CVs to mastering customer interactions, every session was filled with valuable lessons. We delved into computer hardware, troubleshooting techniques, and even wrote our first knowledge base articles.</p> <h2 id="day-11-20">Day 11-20</h2> <p>With each passing day, our skills grew stronger. We navigated through complex labs, tackled cybersecurity concepts, and engaged in mock interviews. Networking opportunities and employer connections fueled our aspirations for the future.</p> <h2 id="day-21-30">Day 21-30</h2> <p>As graduation approached, our focus intensified. We fine-tuned our skills in troubleshooting, communication, and teamwork. Through roleplays and assessments, we gained confidence in our abilities and prepared for the next step in our journey.</p> <h2 id="day-31-45">Day 31-45</h2> <p>In the final stretch, we put our knowledge to the test. From technical assessments to cybersecurity modules, we demonstrated our readiness for the IT industry. Graduation day marked the culmination of our hard work and the beginning of a new chapter in our careers.</p> <h2 id="reflection">Reflection</h2> <p>Looking back on my time with Generation UK, I’m grateful for the invaluable skills and experiences gained. From the first day of bootcamp to graduation, each step has prepared me for success in the dynamic world of IT. As I embark on this journey, I’m excited to apply my newfound knowledge and contribute to the ever-evolving tech landscape.</p> <h2 id="graduation-day">Graduation Day</h2> <p><img src="/assets/img/generation.png" width="100%" height="100%"/></p> <p><img src="/assets/img/generation_certificate.jpg" width="100%" height="100%"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My experience at Generation UK.]]></summary></entry></feed>